AXEL INGADI

Eldoret, Kenya · (+254)714095506 · axelingadi@gmail.com · github.com/ingadi

SUMMARY

Web Developer, Frontend with 7+ years of experience in building delightful, accessible and maintainable user Interfaces.

Skills: Wireframing · Mockups · HTML · CSS · JavaScript (ES6+) · TypeScript · Responsive Design · Component Driven Design · React · Browser APIs · Rest APIs · Serverless platforms such as Firebase · Angular · Ionic · Bootstrap CSS · Test Driven Development · Linux CLI · Git-flow · Agile practices · NPM & other Node CLI based build tools such as Vite / Parcel.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Kava Africa Remote

Front-end Developer (Freelance)

Aug 2021 - Dec 2021

A financial institution specializing in asset management, investment planning, savings strategies, and funds services.

 Created a Dashboard; using HTML, Bootstrap CSS and Angular, for a Restful Backend used internally to track transactions and generate banking reports in CSV format.

Discoucher Remote

UI / UX Designer & Front-end Developer (Freelance)

Jun 2020 – Aug 2021

A startup offering a physical book of annual exclusive 'Get One Free' discount vouchers for Restaurants, Cafes, Hotels, Salons and Spas.

Was tasked with bringing the entire voucher redeeming process online to work alongside book sales, which involved:

- Creating mockups for, then building; using Firebase, Cloudinary, HTML, Bootstrap CSS, and Angular, an admin dashboard to allow for general user and voucher management.
- Creating mockups for, then building; using Angular and Ionic an android application that allowed
 customers to purchase or convert their physical books into subscriptions, as well as enable them to
 redeem vouchers using either the book or the application at various supported establishments.
- Building an android app using Angular and Ionic as part of a simple payment gateway system I
 designed for the startup which significantly reduced their monthly costs.

OTB Africa Remote

UI / UX Designer and Front-end Developer (Freelance)

Oct 2019 – May 2020

A company that specializes in software solutions for Businesses, Governments and NGOs.

• Subcontracted to create mockups and later a website for the county government of Machakos used to showcase and promote various investment opportunities within the county.

DarasaApp Remote

UI / UX Designer and Front-end Developer (Freelance)

Jul 2019 - Oct 2019

An E-learning startup offering practice tests and question banks for university students.

• With feedback from the founder and a Ruby backend developer; created mockups for and built an Android app using Ionic and Angular allowing users to purchase subscriptions to the service.

Hiatus / Sabbatical Feb 2017 – Jul 2019

• Provided 24/7 in-home care for my brother who got diagnosed with a severe long-term neurological disorder.

Used this time to relearn Computer Science concepts such as Data structures and Algorithms.

C4DLab Nairobi, Kenya

Front-end Developer and UX Design instructor

Jan 2015 - Feb 2017

- Maintained the lab's website, including performing a migration from free hosting to Bluehost resulting in better customer care support as well as increased security and page load speeds by 200%.
- As part of a team of 3, created mockups from user needs as well as UI assets for an Android application, Kakuma App – a solution to help refugees in Kakuma refugee camp find each other.
- Worked with a Python (Django) developer to create and onboard Cubermovers (a moving company) to a dashboard system from pen and paper boosting efficiency by at least 300%.
- Mentored and helped incubatees with logo and pitch deck designs which they used in startup pitch competitions to secure funding.
- Subcontracted by Ihub and emobilis (partner startup accelerators) to coach incubates on how to improve UX for their products helping them boost customer acquisition and retention.
- Participated in discussions to identify opportunities, problem areas and process improvements which helped increase efficiency and impact, doubling incubatee and event registrations.

Geoaddress Nairobi, Kenya

Cofounder (Incubate)

Mar 2014 - Dec 2014

- As part of 3 co-founders aiming to solve physical addressing for the developing world, I was
 responsible for articulating the idea i.e. creating copy, logo, and pitch deck designs which we used to
 win incubation at C4DLab giving the team free office space and internet to build out the product.
- Helped create and launch the MVP by designing user flows, implementing the UI for the Web appusing HTML, Bootstrap CSS, AngularJS, and creating UI assets for the Android app.

C4DLab Nairobi, Kenya

Graphic Designer (Intern)

Mar 2014- Sep 2014

- Collaborated with other designers to create the lab's visual branding, i.e. logo, typography and color palette which significantly increased awareness and trust helping land the lab's first partnerships.
- Used Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator to design business cards and elements for PowerPoint presentations used by management in stakeholder meetings.
- Designed posters and certificates for IT training and events hosted by the lab and its partners significantly boosting attendance and revenue.
- Collaborated with Content Marketing and Social Media teams to design graphics for posts boosting engagement by 32%.
- Used Google Drive, Docs and Sheets to document and organize design assets, resources, and processes, later used to effectively train new hires reducing on-boarding time by at least 50%.

EDUCATION

University Of Nairobi

Nairobi, Kenya

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

• Grade: Upper Second-Class Honours